<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Welcome on Haoruo Zhang's Personal Website</title><link>https://ezhanghz.onrender.com/tags/welcome/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on Haoruo Zhang's Personal Website</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.141.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:31:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ezhanghz.onrender.com/tags/welcome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://ezhanghz.onrender.com/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:55:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ezhanghz.onrender.com/posts/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello there!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student in MAE at Nanyang Technological University. My research focuses on Human-Machine Interaction/Collaboration, leveraging the transformative power of AI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During my Master&amp;rsquo;s training, I delved into multiple research fields, including but not limited to Data Science, Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Robotics, and Large Language Models. Just as I embarked on my Master&amp;rsquo;s journey, OpenAI released the groundbreaking LLM application, ChatGPT. Scholars from diverse disciplines began exploring the capabilities of LLMs in their respective fields, and I was no exception. By integrating LLMs with various domains, I realized that while the transformer architecture marks an impressive leap in deep learning, the true revolution brought by LLMs lies in the way they redefine our interaction with data—and machines.&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello there!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m a PhD student in MAE at Nanyang Technological University. My research focuses on Human-Machine Interaction/Collaboration, leveraging the transformative power of AI.</p>
<p>During my Master&rsquo;s training, I delved into multiple research fields, including but not limited to Data Science, Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Robotics, and Large Language Models. Just as I embarked on my Master&rsquo;s journey, OpenAI released the groundbreaking LLM application, ChatGPT. Scholars from diverse disciplines began exploring the capabilities of LLMs in their respective fields, and I was no exception. By integrating LLMs with various domains, I realized that while the transformer architecture marks an impressive leap in deep learning, the true revolution brought by LLMs lies in the way they redefine our interaction with data—and machines.</p>
<p>Currently, we are confident that LLMs have absolute no idea of what they read and what they say. They simply predict and generate token sequences based on probabilistic patterns. I don&rsquo;t know if we will ever talk with a sentient machine. However, the millions of users engaging with LLM tools demonstrate that even a statistical illusion of intelligence is enough to fundamentally alter how humans interact with technology. Perhaps, as these interactions suggest, we aren&rsquo;t as uniquely creative or statistically special as we like to think (´･_･`).</p>
<p>Deep learning techniques will continue to evolve. More powerful models will emerge, surpassing the current state-of-the-art. However, the paradigm shift has already occurred. Even if LLM eventually becomes obselete, the way we communicate with machines—and the expectations we have of them—will never return to what they once were.</p>
<p>During my PhD study, I aim to explore how computers and robots can communicate and collaborate with humans in ways that are more intuitive, efficient, approachable, and safe. I believe that for machines to be truly effective partners, they must adapt to the diverse and often unpredictable needs of their human collaborators. This includes developing systems that understand context, recognize human intent, and interact in ways that feel natural while maintaining reliability and trustworthiness.</p>
<p>Through my research, I hope to contribute to a future where humans and machines work together seamlessly, unlocking new possibilities for innovation and creativity. I’m excited to navigate the challenges and opportunities that come with bridging the gap between human intuition and computational precision.</p>
<p>Besides academics and research, I&rsquo;m also interested in gaming, camping, biking, and sailing. I enjoy exploring the outdoors and unfamiliar corners of cities with two wheels. Perhaps the next step is to learn how to capture them with camera or pigments.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>